Alejandro Torres

Bend, Oregon; (503) 734-4761; alejandro.torres.photography@gmail.com

Experienced IT Project Manager with strong leadership and relationship-building skills. Alejandro is a strategic, forward-thinking mind with a combined 12+ years of data analytics, business analysis, and IT project management experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TRAVELING SABBATICAL

Jun 2016 - Feb 2018

- Traveled around the world exploring and developing new skills and abilities where I accomplished the following:
 - o Ran two full marathons in less than a year in Iceland and Guatemala.
 - Guided a visually impaired athlete to finish a 10K running race in 42 minutes for the first time. Volunteered at Yo Soy Sus Ojos, Peruvian organization that empowers visually impaired athletes.
 - Worked as a Hotel Manager for 6 months in one of the top 25 boutique hotels in the world. Upheld the high service standards from the moment clients arrived with a warm welcome on the dock, a property tour, daily activity planning with room service and maintenance team, coordination of private transportation and seamless check-out procedure at Lake Atitlan, Guatemala.
 - 200hr Yoga Teacher Training Association of Yoga and Meditation Rishikesh, India
 - o 150hr Thai Massage Course Dr. Bann and Joi Pantila Pai, Thailand

PEPSICO FOODS, FRITO LAY (Peru & Ecuador)

Supply Chain IT Project Manager and Process Support

Jan 2010 – May 2016

- Implemented and supported automation of the supply chain process using JDA Demand Planner and Distribution Replenishment Plan, reducing forecasting time by 85%.
- Led the implementation of a Warehouse Management System solution. This allowed the company to move from manual processes to completely digital, reducing 95% human mistakes and improving dispatch time by 40%.
- Supported Oracle Process Manufacture (OPM) and Financial Management modules, by Oracle EBS ERP, for incidents and requirements.

IT Financial Analyst

Jan 2010 - May 2016

- Managed \$8 Million IT budget with less than 3% variation year over year.
- Negotiated with IT service providers (telecommunications, consulting, networking) and optimizing resources resulting in savings of \$100K every year.
- Created a new IT-oriented financial tracking and planning model for technology service expenses. This enabled the ability to create immediate financial reporting on demand.

Business Intelligence Analyst

Apr 2006 - Jan 2010

- Built and supported a Business Intelligence financial solution in order to obtain NOPBT per product and client; report preparation was dramatically reduced by nearly 90% in 2008.
- Managed and supported the Sales and Distribution business intelligence solution and directed the training process for 240 key users including department executives.

• Collaborated successfully with cross-functional teams to design and develop new operating reports.

Regional IT Analyst

Mar 2004 - Apr 2006

- Led the implementation of a Desktop Virtualization solution offering an architecture technology able to support the deployment of 9 distribution centers over 3 years.
- Collaborated with the implementation team of a new sales and distribution software. This enabled a
 more efficient sales process and full integration between sales and inventory data.
- Both projects stated above allowed the company to increase sales by 50% between 2006 and 2008.

EDUCATION

Master in Business Administration

PAD, Escuela de Dirección de la Universidad de Piura, 2010

• Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Software Engineering

Universidad Peruana de Ciencias Aplicadas, 2003

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Analytics Individual Certification Google, 2018
- Budget construction and control Pepsico University, 2013
- Supply Chain Management and Financial Analysis PepsiCo University, 2012
- ITIL v 3.0 Certification Pepsico University, 2011
- Six Sigma Certification Universidad de Lima Lima, Peru, 2010
- IT Project Management ESAN Lima, Peru, 2008

INTERESTS

- Marathon runner (x8); currently training for 9th.
- Avid yoga practitioner since 2011.
- Travel and landscape photographer since 2004: www.alejandrotorresphotography.com